（欢快的音乐）
(upbeat music)
- 在这个视频中，我会向你
- In this video, I'm going to give you
快速介绍一下我们的 Transformer 模型
a very quick introduction to how our transformer models
是如何跟 Tensorflow 和 Keras 一起工作。
work together with Tensorflow and Keras.
简单地说
The very short explanation
我们所有的 Tensorflow 模型
is that all of our Tensorflow models
也是 Keras 模型对象，
are also Keras model objects,
因此它们拥有标准的 Keras 模型 API。
and so they have the standard Keras model API.
如果你是一位经验丰富的机器学习工程师，
If you're an experienced machine learning engineer
并且经常使用Keras的话，这可能就是你使用它们
who's used Keras a lot, that's probably all you need to know
所需要知道的全部内容。
to start working with them.
但对其他人来说，
But for everyone else,
包括那些想要使用 Keras 的
including the prodigal PyTorch engineers out there
PyTorch 工程师们
who are returning to the fold,
我将快速介绍 Keras 模型，
I'm going to quickly introduce Keras models,
以及我们如何使用它们。
and how we work with them.
在下面链接的其他视频中，
In other videos, which I'll link below,
我将更详细地介绍 Keras 模型的训练。
I'll run through training with Keras models in more detail.
但首先，从高层次上讲，什么是 Keras 模型？
But first, at a high level, what is a Keras model?
你的模型基本上包含了你的整个网络。
So your model basically contains your entire network.
它包含层，以及这些层的权重，
It contains the layers, and the weights for those layers,
并告诉模型如何处理它们
and also tells the model what to do with them
所以从你的输入到你的输出
so it defines the whole path all the way
它完整定义了整个路径。
from your inputs to your outputs.
如果你以前使用过 Keras，
If you've used Keras before,
你可能是从自己动手构建模型对象
you probably started using model objects
开始使用它们的，
by building them out by hand,
你添加了一层又一层
you added one layer after another
并且可能使用了 model.add () 或功能性的方法。
and maybe using the model.add () or the functional approach.
这并没有错。
And there's nothing wrong with that.
许多伟大的模型都是以这种方式构建的
Lots of great models are built that way
但你也可以预加载整个模型、权重等等。
but you can also pre-load an entire model, weights and all.
这真的很有帮助，因为如果你，
And this is really helpful, because if you,
正如你在这里看到的，如果你尝试阅读这篇论文
as you can see here, if you try reading the paper
或者如果你尝试查看代码，
or if you try looking at the code,
你会发现 Transformer 的内部非常复杂，
you'll see the inside of a Transformer is pretty complex,
从头开始把它写出来并把它做好
and writing it all out from scratch and getting it right
即使对于有经验的机器学习工程师来说
would be hard even for an experienced
也很难。
machine learning engineer.
但因为它都打包装在一个模型里，
But because it's all packed inside a model,
如果你不想理解模型的复杂性的话，
you don't need to worry about that complexity on that
你就完全不需要担心它。
if you don't want to.
如果你是一名研究人员，如果你想真正深入研究
If you're a researcher, if you want to really dig in there
你可以，但你也可以只用一行代码加载一个
you can, but you can also just load a pre-trained,
预训练预配置的 Transformer 模型。
pre-configured transformer model in just one line of code.
我之前提到了 Keras API，
And when I mentioned earlier about the Keras API,
它的优点是
the advantage of it is that
不管你是从头开始编写自己的模型
whether you write your own model from scratch
还是加载一个预训练的模型，你可以通过相同的 API
or load a pre-trained one, you interact with the model
来与模型交互，所以你其实只要用
through that same API, so you use exactly
同样的几种方法，你会一次又一次地
the same few methods and you're gonna see them
看到它们，这些方法比如 fit，
again and again, these methods like fit,
complie 和 predict，就像我之前提到的
compile and predict, and like I've mentioned
我们将在下面链接的视频中介绍如何
we'll cover concrete examples of how to use those methods
使用这些方法的具体示例。
in the videos I'll link below.
现在这个视频最关键的点，
For now the key thing to take away from this video,
如果你以前从未见过 Keras 的话，
if you've never seen Keras before,
是这种简洁的封装意味着
is that this neat encapsulation means
一个巨大且复杂的神经网络
that all the complexity of a huge neural net
变得易于管理，因为你以完全相同的方式
becomes manageable, because you interact with it
使用完全相同的方法，与它交互，
in exactly the same way, using exactly the same methods,
不管它是一个庞大的预训练语言模型
whether it's a huge pre-trained language model
还是一个你手写的简单模型。
or a simple model that you wrote out by hand.
（欢快的音乐）
(upbeat music)